Jonah Alligood

Highly motivated software engineer with over four years of professional experience. Particularly strong in the areas of web technologies and backend development. Looking for new opportunities offering tech ownership and meaningful impact with the ultimate goal of adding value to the organization.

Saint Louis, MO
(309) 750-7752
mail@byjonah.net
https://www.linkedin.com/in/
jonah-alligood/

EXPERIENCE

Mastercard, O'Fallon, MO — Senior Software Engineer

AUGUST 2023 - PRESENT

- Working in cryptographic security, specifically writing in-house software to securely create, manage, and distribute cryptographic keys to various servers and HSMs.
- Leading development of a pipeline program for the purposes of validating incoming policy configurations from clients intending to utilize our distribution service.
- Mentoring younger and less experienced engineers to help grow them in healthy engineering and professional habits

World Wide Technology, St. Louis, MO — Developer

FEBRUARY 2022 - AUGUST 2023

- Developed an internal risk management tool in React and Spring Boot using Agile and TDD principles.
- Developed and tested EDI and RosettaNet integrations with partners using webMethods and PL/SQL.
- Developed and tested internal applications for the purposes of monitoring partner integrations and managing hardware and software rebates with select vendors.
- Supported team in an on-call rotation to ensure that our integrations were running smoothly, and take care of any maintenance windows.

Precision Planting, Peoria, IL— Junior Software Engineer

JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2021

- Developed a memory mapping command line tool for the purpose of converting various ELF dump formats into a unified internal file format to be parsed at a later date by an in-house debugger.
- Worked with a small team to develop and maintain an in-house CAN bus reader and writer.
- Created and owned another command line project to generate C++ type definitions for CAN bus packets to be used in other software.
- Maintained parts of the 20|20 in-cab device orchestrator and data reader.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois, Springfield, IL— B.S. Computer Science

AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2022

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, React, Vue, Node, Express, Tailwind, C++, PHP

PROJECTS

Cube With Me (2022)

- Developed a speed cubing website for users to race one another.
- Service included the ability to create and join rooms.
- Implemented WebSockets to functionally drive the backend state of rooms.

IEngine2D (2020)

- Created a 2D game engine mostly for myself for use in Ludum Dare game jams.
- Supports OpenGL 3+ for rendering.
- Includes features like sprite sheets, font rendering, and audio playback.

<u>Just Listen (2019)</u>

- Created a service for musicians to link their discography on every platform.
- Developed a Spotify integration to import an artist's existing discography.

You can find the rest of my portfolio <u>here</u>.